MARIO RUDY SILALAHI

PROGRAMMER

+6281327532014 | mariosihaloho700@gmail.com | mario-silalahi.vercel.app | linkedin.com/in/mario-rudy-silalahi | Purwokerto, Jawa Tengah, Indonesia

PROFILE

A Bachelor of Informatics Engineering from the Telkom Institute of Technology Purwokerto. Enjoys working collaboratively in a team. Has a keen interest in programming, with 1.5 years of internship and freelance experience, especially in web development. Capable of implementing clean and readable code in projects using the programming languages required by the company. Aspires to become a senior software developer/programmer.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PT Sagara Technology (Jan 2024 - Mar 2024)

Frontend Developer | Freelance

- Collaborated in a team using the Scrum methodology to develop a laptop product sales website.
- Implemented the Auth feature and product pages, from design slicing to API integration for approximately 5 pages.
- Implemented the Product CMS feature from the Admin side.
- Completed phase 1 of the project by contributing to approximately 40% of the MVP features (Auth, product selection, Product CMS).

PT Menara Pengetahuan Indonesia (Feb 2023 – Jun 2023)

Frontend Developer | Intern

- Collaborated in a team using the Scrum methodology to develop two websites, "Kampus Gratis" and served as the intern lead on the "Learning Experience Platform" project, completing the beta version and MVP features.
- Converted layouts and integrated APIs for over 10 responsive pages.
- Involved in testing more than 5 API endpoints using Postman.

PT Egrotek / Kedaireka Project (Jun 2022 - Des 2022)

Frontend Developer | Intern

- Developed an IoT device monitoring platform and completed 3 MVP features (Auth, Dashboard, Device) for the initial version of the website.
- Involved in designing the UI for the dashboard application across 2 pages (Dashboard and Auth).

EDUCATION

• Institut Teknologi Telkom Purwokerto (2020 – 2024) | Informatics Engineering / GPA 3.99

Award: Speaker at the Centive 2023 National Seminar

Relevant Courses: Basic Programming, Functional Programming, Object-Oriented Programming, Web Programming, Semantic Web, Algorithms and Data Structures, Database Systems. Software Project.

Final Project: Implementation of Responsive Progressive Web App in Developing the Point of Sale Application for Ecoprint MSMEs (Case Study: Cemantingart Purbalingga).

• SMK Telkom Sandy Putra Purwokerto (2017 – 2020) | Computer and Network Engineering

Award: Participant in the APJII Network Olympiad Regional Central Java & DIY 2019, Recipient of the OPES Scholarship (Telkom Education Foundation).

Relevant Courses: Fundamentals of Programming Algorithms

CERTIFICATE

- BNSP Certification (2024) | Junior Web Developer Occupational Scheme
- Kedaireka Internship Program (2022) | Frontend Developer
- MSIB Internship Program (2023) | Frontend Developer

SKILL

- **Programming Languages**: Javascript (experienced), Typescript (experienced), MySQL (basic), PHP (basic), Python (basic), C++ (basic), Java (basic)
- Website Development: HTML (experienced), CSS (experienced), Tailwind CSS (experienced), React JS (experienced), Next JS (experienced), Laravel (basic), Express JS (basic), REST API (basic), UI Design (experienced), Redux (basic)
- Tools: Visual Studio Code, Webstrom, Postman, Figma, Trello,, Github, Gitlab
- SoftSkill: Team Work, Time Management, Hardwork, Multitasking.

ORGANIZATIONAL EXPERIENCE

• Faculty of Informatics Student Council (2021 - 2022) | Coordinator of the Household Affairs Division

LAST PROJECT

- **Point of Sales,** Developed a Point of Sale application for CemantingArt MSMEs (Purbalingga) by implementing Progressive Web Apps on the frontend using Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, and Ant Design.
- Zyrex Maveric, Pengembangan website penjualan produk dari brand zyrex untuk sisi pelanggan dan sisi admin dari sisi frontend dengan teknologi Next JS, Typescript, Tailwind CSS, Ant Design, dan state management dengan recoil
- Personal Portfolio, Developed a personal portfolio website using React Vite and Tailwind CSS.